<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Notes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there. My intent with this site is to share useful analytic ideas and tools - from basic to advanced - that have made my work easier and more fun.
Current Employment I am a research principal in Gartner&amp;rsquo;s finance practice. I currently use quantitative and qualitative research methods to answer hard questions for chief financial officers and their finance teams. I have been in a related role at CEB (now Gartner) for thirteen years, with visits to the worlds of product development and management, sales support and client advisory services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me a note to book me as a team or conference speaker for your organization, or just to say hi.
Your name  Your email  Your message
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>I will mostly use R and Python in these notes and case studies. Both languages have fantastic resources to help you access the relevant software and packages for data analysis use-cases whether you&amp;rsquo;re using MacOS, Windows or a Linux instance.
Installing R Install the R language
Install the R-Studio IDE
Installing Python Install Anaconda
Anaconda installs the latest version of the Python language (if you&amp;rsquo;re new to this, use version 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of football fan tweets during a game</title>
      <link>/post/sentiment-analysis-of-football-fans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sentiment-analysis-of-football-fans/</guid>
      <description>Are Manchester United fans more critical of their team than opposing fans about theirs? This was the (too ambitious) question I intended to answer when I began this piece but having discovered some of the difficulties in accessing bulk, multi-period Twitter data I have scaled it back. I certainly intend to revist the bigger question using Twitter scraping solutions that have since become available, but for now I’ll restrict myself to the more achievable question:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing scientific notation in R</title>
      <link>/post/r-scipen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-scipen/</guid>
      <description>options(scipen = 999) #the command that turns off scientific notation in R output I often set this parameter in any R project in which I’ll be evaluating predictive model performance. But why would you want to turn off scientific notation?
Scientific notation is shorthand for large number strings. For example:
 The number 0.00000000002 is written in R output in the scientific notation format as 2e-11
 Basically, this approach takes the integer “2”, puts a decimal point in front of it (1 of the 11), and counts off the remainder of the e-numbers (10) as decimal places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>