<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Data Notes</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Data Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OLS Regression Part 1: Basics</title>
      <link>/post/interpreting-ols-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/interpreting-ols-regression/</guid>
      <description>I recommend this book to help you understand where ordinary least squares (OLS) regression fits within the most common statistical learning approaches:
James et al., An Introduction to Statistical Learning: with Applications in R (Springer Texts in Statistics) 1st ed. 2013, Corr. 7th printing 2017 Edition
With so many options available to students and practitioners it is rare to find a book that takes both an accessible-theoretical and practical approach to econometrics and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis of Football Fan Tweets During a Game</title>
      <link>/post/sentiment-analysis-of-football-fans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sentiment-analysis-of-football-fans/</guid>
      <description>Are Manchester United fans more critical of their team than opposing fans about theirs? This was the (too ambitious) question I intended to answer when I began this piece but having discovered some of the difficulties in accessing bulk, multi-period Twitter data I have scaled it back. I certainly intend to revisit the bigger question using Twitter scraping solutions that have since become available, but for now I’ll restrict myself to the more achievable question:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Tips #1: Turning Off and On Scientific Notation</title>
      <link>/post/r-tips-1-scientific-notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-tips-1-scientific-notation/</guid>
      <description>options(scipen = 999) #the command that turns off scientific notation in R output I often set this parameter in any R project in which I’ll be evaluating predictive model performance. But why would you want to turn off scientific notation? First, it’s a personal preference, but I strongly advocate for learning how to read scientific notation as it is a data science standard. Second, your audience may not be mathematically trained.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>